

Andre Christoga Pramaditya

PROFILE

Was born in Jakarta on March 2004

16 years old Age

Status Physics Undergraduate at the

University of Indonesia

Residence Jakarta, Indonesia **Email** caxvis@gmail.com WhatsApp +(62) 85 1010 93410

Site https://drepram.com

SOCIAL MEDIA

Andre Christoga Pramaditya

@drepram

@drepram

ACTIVITIES

- · Member of the Indonesian Army **Technology Community**
- · Member of the Indonesia Artificial Intelligence Society

WHAT I DO BEST

Web Development

HTML, CSS, VanillaJS, Bulma, Bootstrap (3+)

JavaScript

ES6, Node.js, React, VueJS, TypeScript, ExpressJS, Redux, Redux-Saga, MongoDB

Other

Python, Linux (basic), Git, SQL, SQLite, MySQL, JWT, Docker

Take a look at my LinkedIn profile for work experiences, projects, and even more achievements.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Invited to attend South East Asia Machine Learning Summer School 2019

at the University of Indonesia

Was selected as the only high-school student that was eligible to attend a summer school attended by undergraduates, graduates and doctoral students across Asia, Australia and Europe

Member of the Organizing Committee of Smart Hackathon 2018 2018 The First Nation-wide High-School Hackathon supported by the Ministry of Education and Culture (MoEC) and the Ministry of

Judge of Smart Hackathon 2018

2017 Winner of FWD Insurance Hackathon, FWD Insurance

Communication and Technology (MoCT)

• Developed "FWDGo", an AR Advertising Platform

Graduated Secondary School by the age of 13

Become "The Young Programmer" (Programmer Cilik) star 2016 for Ministry of Health (MoH) and Ministry of Communication and

Technology (MoCT) of Indonesia

Become the star of "Programmer Cilik" (Young Programmer) Documentary Movie, Funded by Ministry of Health and Metro TV

Interviewed by Microsoft's CEO, Mr. Satya Nadella for building a VR Publishing Platform and for being the "Young Programmer" icon

Winner of The First Digital Media Hackathon in Indonesia, Microsoft and Tempo

• Developed "GoVRnor", VR publishing platform about Jakarta's government election.

Winner of Code for the Kingdom Hackathon, Kejora Ventures

• Developed "PUTIK", a digital gospel music streaming service to help isolated church cell group to grow.

2015 Graduated Elementary School by the age of 11

> Finalist of Hackathon Merdeka, held by Kantor Staf Presiden of Indonesia in Merdeka Palace, at age 11 years old

Finalist of Hackathon Merdeka 2.0, held by Telkomsel and Code4Nation, at age 11 years old

Promoted by the CTO of Amazon, Werner Vogels

Published in various well-established mass media:

2 times in The Jakarta Post magazine (weekly and annual magazine), JawaPos newspaper, TribunNews, Kompas TV, and many more

Black Belt Karateka, Athlete, Instructure Senpai

at Smart Dojo at age 10

Personal Statement

Andre Christoga Pramaditya Physics, Class of 2020

In life, I believe one's strengths and weaknesses cannot be separated from one's family background, education, and the natural talents of every individual. Henceforth, my life story is essential in shaping my strength and weaknesses.

Every individual has their own strengths and weaknesses. In accomplishing my goals, I've learned that life itself is a learning experience for me to always get better and wiser. So, what are my greatest strength and weakness?

My greatest strength is that I am a curious and initiative learner. I'm always curious about how the world works, what obstacle the world has to overcome, and how I, as an individual in a computer science field, can make the world a better place. Most of the time, I'm reading books about world history, computer science, and natural science, finding new things to learn every day, and continuously challenging myself to be better. My passion for programming and science also comes from these traits, finding problems, and come up with solutions. In short, my closest friends and colleagues will describe me as a creative, insightful, and passionate individual.

My shortcomings might be due to my perfectionist traits. By being a perfectionist, I do many things slower than others. Since I always want my work to be done perfectly, I tend to invest more energy and thoughts on a subject rather than working on and complete things. While this is a wonderful quality in many ways - making me always do things better - but as I grow up, I began to understand that in many ways, an ideal and 'perfect' situation is not always possible. My experiences in participating in coding competitions and karate tournaments help to shape me to be a much more decisive person today and in the future.

Hopefully, by identifying my strengths and weaknesses above, I can grow into a well-rounded individual with the mission to make the world a better place through science. I believe studying at the University of Indonesia would be the perfect opportunity for me to learn and experience new cultures, find new insights and philosophy, and embrace new opportunities.

Experience

Andre Christoga Pramaditya's $(\ensuremath{\textit{drepram}})$ professional and other experience

Kebon Bawang, Tanjung Priok Jakarta Utara, DKI Jakarta, Indonesia 14320 (62) 8889-835-837 (62) 85-1010-934-10 caxvis@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

PT. MEGANA for **Smesco Indonesia**, Remote — *Back-end Developer (Contract)*

FEBRUARY 2020 - MAY 2020

Contracted to create one of the agency's platform infrastructure for SMEs, **Sparc Trac**. More details regarding the technologies down below.

PT. Sukses Smart Sistem, North Jakarta — *Remote API Engineer (Contract)*

SEPTEMBER 2019 - DECEMBER 2019

Built the API and designed the database schema for a property listing platform. Worked with Express, Axios, Passport, Nodemailer & MongoDB.

PT. Mercy Toga Kirana, North Jakarta — *Software Engineer (Part-time)*

JANUARY 2019 - JULY 2019

Maintain existing websites and craft new ones with React & Tailwind. Also crafted a RESTful API for a student management system.

Konvergen.ai, Central Jakarta — Software Engineering Intern

MARCH 2019 - AUGUST 2019

Built a dataset management platform, and worked with Express, React, Redux and Redux-Saga. The job also helped me learn some compression APIs in Node.js and how to work with GCP's storage.

If of any relevance: all of the work I have done above was using Git as its version control.

EDUCATION

PKBM MERCY SMART, Indonesia — High School Diploma

JUNE 2017 - JUNE 2020

Graduated with an 87,50 average.

LANGUAGES

- English: Fluent (7.0 in IELTS)

- Indonesian: Native

RELATED SOCIAL

- github.com/drepram
- <u>linkedin.com/in/drepram/</u>

PROJECTS

Genesis — Fighting fake news with encoding

Genesis is an initiative that me and my team came up for Break the Fake hackathon, a hackathon that aims to fight fake news. The project function was to inject certain zero-width characters into broadcast texts in order to make it able to be traced back. The project was built with React and takes advantage of JavaScript encoding function.

PROJECTS

Sparc Trac — Ministry of *SME* infrastructure

Sparc Trac is a stamping platform that's marketed to SMEs in Indonesia. The initiator of the project was Smesco Indonesia, a public service agency under the Ministry of Cooperatives and SMEs. I built the back-end system in Node.js with Express, MongoDB, and PDF generation.

ORGANIZATION

Evil Factory Labs — Web Technology Society/Publication

We are a collection of Indonesian software engineers that write articles on multiple topics such as Compilers, and Parallel Computing, and many more. I'm currently preparing a draft regarding the setup of email service and PDF-to-MD generation in Node.js.

https://github.com/evilfactorylabs